Barry Commoner Papers
Manuscript Division, Library of Congress
- 1990 Addition, 1943-1979 (Box 442-491)
  - Subject File, 1948-1978 (Box 452-466)
    - Fossil fuels. 1971-1973, (2 folders) (Box 456)
    - Foreign policy, 1965-1972, undated, (6 folders) (Box 457)
    - Fortune 500 letter drive, 1972 (Box 458)
    - Fund for Peace, 1972-1978, (3 folders) (Box 458)
    - Geological prospecting process and apparatus, patent application Canada, 1957-1963, (2 folders) (Box 458)
    - Grants (Box 459)
      - Applications, 1948-1958 (Box 459)
      - General, 1972-1974, undated, (2 folders) (Box 459)
    - Hapgood, Charles, 1955-1958 (Box 459)
    - Human health, undated (Box 459)
    - "In the Public Interest," 1973-1974 (Box 459)
    - Lefrak, Samuel, suit, 1974, undated (Box 459)
    - Medical Tribune, 1974, undated (Box 459)
    - Molecular biology (Box 460)
      - Committee (Box 460)
        - General, 1956-1965, (3 folders) (Box 460)
        - Minutes, 1959-1965 (Box 460)
      - Forms, undated (Box 460)
      - Qualifying exams, 1960-1963 (Box 460)
    - Mount Sinai School of Medicine, Biology Department, New York, N. Y., 1969 (Box 460)
    - National Academy of Sciences, 1963-1966 (Box 460)
    - National Council for the Environment, undated (Box 460)
    - Nitrate (Box 460)
      - Correspondence (Box 460)
        - 1967-1969 (Box 460)
        - 1968-1969, (3 folders) (Box 461)
      - General, 1969-1970 (Box 462)
    - Nitrogen, 1969-1971, undated (Box 462)
    - "N" miscellany, 1959, 1965-1966, undated, (2 folders) (Box 462)
    - "O" miscellany, 1965-1966 (Box 462)
    - Patents, 1955-1959 (Box 462)
    - Poland paper, 1973, (2 folders) (Box 462)
    - Poland paper, 1973 (Box 463)
    - Publishers, 1964-1966 (Box 463)
    - "P" miscellany, 1964-1966 (Box 463)
    - "Q" miscellany, 1965-1966 (Box 463)
    - Research program, 1963 (Box 463)
    - "R" miscellany, 1965-1966 (Box 463)
    - Scientists Institute for Public Information, 1972 (Box 463)
    - Sigma XI, 1956-1966 (Box 463)
    - Smithsonian Institution, Washington, D.C., 1964-1966 (Box 463)
    - Social Science Institute, 1965 (Box 463)
    - Sutton, William B., 1957-1958 (Box 463)
    - Synthetic fuel industry, 1971-1974 (Box 463)
    - Synthetic fuel industry, 1971-1974, (2 folders) (Box 464)
    - Szent-Gyorgyi, Albert, 1961-1965 (Box 464)
    - "S" miscellany, 1965-1966, 1971 (Box 464)
    - Technology, 1970-1974, (2 folders) (Box 464)
    - Technology, 1970-1974 (Box 465)
    - Transportation, railroads, 1971-1974, (3 folders) (Box 465)
    - Trips (Box 465)
      - France, 1971 (Box 465)
      - Italy, 1973 (Box 465)
      - New York, 1970-1972, (3 folders) (Box 465)
      - Washington, D.C., 1971 (Box 466)
    - "T" miscellany, 1965-1966 (Box 466)
    - Urban rat control, 1968-1970 (Box 466)
    - "U" miscellany, 1964-1966 (Box 466)
    - Washington University, St. Louis, Mo., 1965-1966 (Box 466)
    - Weapons, 1974 (Box 466)
    - Working environment, 1972-1974 (Box 466)
  - Research File (Box 466-485)
    Charts, graphs, computer printouts, and other research data.
    Arranged alphabetically by topic or type of material.
    - Auxin (Box 466)
    - Charts and graphs (Box 466-470)
    - Computer printouts See containers OV 1-3, same heading (Box OV 1-OV 3)
    - Demography See also container OV 4, same heading (Box 471-474)
    - Diet, (2 folders) (Box 475)
    - DNA (Box 476-477)
    - Electron spin resonance (Box 478-482)
    - Free radicals (Box 483-484)
    - Tobacco mosaic virus (Box 484-485)
  - Photographs and Slides (Box R 486-487)
    Photographs, slides, and transparencies. Broken glass slides are restricted.
    - Broken glass slides (Restricted) See Container 487, Slides (Box R 486)
    - Photographs, (2 folders) (Box 487)
    - Slides (photocopies of broken glass slides in container R 486) (Box 487)
    - Transparencies See containers OV 5-OV 14, same heading (Box OV 5-OV 14)
  - Miscellany (Box 488-491)
    Awards and certificates, clippings, physiology notes, telephone logs, printed matter, and other miscellaneous items.
    - Awards and certificates (Box 488)
    - Clippings (Box 488)
    - Clippings (Box 489)
    - Clippings (Box 490)
    - Physiology, notes (Box 490)
    - Telephone logs and lists (Box 490)
    - World War II service material, 1942 (Box 490)
    - Clippings and printed matter, (5 folders) (Box 491)
  - Oversize for 1990 Addition (Box OV 1-14)
    Computer printouts and demographic data from Commoner's research file and a set of transparencies from the photographs and slides file.
    Arranged and described according to the series, containers, and folders from which the items were separated.
    - Research file (Box OV 1-OV 4)
      - Computer printouts, 1961, undated (Box OV 1-3)
      - Demography (Container 474, same heading) (Box OV 4)
    - Photographs and Slides (Box OV 5-OV 14)
      - Transparencies (Container 487, same heading) (Box OV 5-OV 14)
- 2019 Addition, 1936-2009 (Box 492-528)
  The 2019 Addition contains material received in 2011 and 2014. This addition is arranged into four subseries and oversize. Material from organizations represented in the Organizations File of the original collection is placed in the Subject File.
  Arranged alphabetically into four subseries and oversize: Clippings File, Research File, Speeches and Writings and Subject File.
  - Clippings File, 1951-2000 (Box 492-495)
    Newspaper and magazine clippings about Commoner from a wide array of publications. Clippings were removed from binders, kept in original order, and generally photocopied for preservation.
    - 1951-1969, (8 folders) (Box 492)
    - 1970-1975, (7 folders) (Box 493)
    - 1976-1979, (9 folders) (Box 494)
    - 1980-2000, (4 folders) (Box 495)
  - Research File, 1936-1978 (Box 495-497)
    Notebooks, notes, and drafts of scientific research projects and studies by Commoner.
    Arranged alphabetically by name of research topic or type of material.
    - Bibliography and abstracts notebook, circa 1958 (Box 495)
    - "Chemical Identification, Distribution Kinetics and Metabolism in vivo of a New Mutagen Detected in Beef Extract and in Cooked Beef," proposal, 1978 (Box 495)
    - "Free Nucleotides in Bird Erythrocytes," notebook, 1966-1967 (Box 495)
    - "Free Radicals I," notebook, 1952-1957 (Box 495)
    - "Free Radicals II," notebook, 1959 (Box 496)
    - "Mechanisms of Chemical Carcinogenesis," final report, circa 1976 (Box 496)
    - "Metabolism and DNA Project, progress report," 1969 (Box 496)
    - Nitrogen cycle project, 1969 (Box 496)
    - Notes and drafts (Box 496)
      - Inheritance, circa 1965, (2 folders) (Box 496)
      - Miscellaneous, undated (Box 496)
      - Viruses, circa 1966 (Box 496)
    - "Physical Mechanisms of Biological Electron Transport: Progress Report," (Box 496)
      - 1959 (Box 496)
      - 1963 (Box 497)
    - "Physical Mechanisms of Biological Electron Transport: Progress Report," 1963 (Box 497)
    - "Respiration" notebook, 1936-1937 (Box 497)
    - Unlabeled notebooks, 1947, undated, (2 folders) (Box 497)
    - "Warburg Apparatus Data" notebook, circa 1959 (Box 497)
  - Speeches and Writings, 1942-2009 (Box 497-514)
    The Speeches and Writings subseries includes book drafts, a chronological file of published articles, speeches, testimonies, and related material. The chronological file reveals Commoner's shifting interests over time and includes a mix of writings on scientific research, public policy, and political issues. The book drafts and reviews of Commoner's books include Air Pollution, Making Peace with the Planet, and The Poverty of Power. The speaking engagements file contains correspondence, publicity, itineraries, travel arrangements, and sometimes speech texts or notes and is chronologically arranged. The speech, conference papers, and testimonies file is also arranged chronologically but only contains the written texts.
    Material types include drafts and published writings, speech texts, related correspondence and printed matter, itineraries, and travel material.
    Arranged alphabetically by type of writing and chronologically therein; the book file is arranged alphabetically.
    - Articles (Box 497)
      - 1942, "The Mechanism of Auxin Action" (Box 497)
      - 1943, "The Mechanism of Auxin Action. The Effect of Auxin on Water Absorbtion by Potato Tuber Tissue" (Box 497)
      - 1947, "The Beginning of Life" (Box 497)
      - 1958, "The Fallout Problem" and "The Hazard of Fallout" (Box 497)
      - 1962, "The Scientist and Political Power--Some Brief Comments" (Box 497)
      - 1963 (Box 498)
        - "Government Research Grants: Effect of the New Proceedures on the Individual Investigator" (Box 498)
        - "Is Science Getting Out of Hand?" (Box 498)
        - "The Roles of Deoxyribonucleic Acid in Inheritance" (Box 498)
        - "Science and the Race Problem" (Box 498)
        - "Scientific Statesmanship" (Box 498)
      - 1964 (Box 498)
        - "Biology Today" (Box 498)
        - "Civil Defense: The Citizen's Choice" (Box 498)
        - "DNA and the Chemistry of Inheritance" (Box 498)
        - "Fallout and Water Pollution--Parallel Cases" (Box 498)
        - "Rapid Biosynthetic Incorporation of C14--Labeled Amino Acids into Tobacco Mosaic Virus" (Box 498)
        - "The Responsibility of Science to Man" (Box 498)
        - "What is the Harm of Nuclear Testing to Human Inheritance?" (Box 498)
      - 1965 (Box 498)
        - "Biochemical, Biological, and Atmospheric Evolution" (Box 498)
        - "Changes in Electron Spin Resonance Signals of Rat Liver during Chemical Carcinogenesis" (Box 498)
        - "Conservation of the Water Resource: The Responsibility of the Scientist" (Box 498)
        - "Effects of Isotopic Substitution on Electron Spin Resonance Signals in Photosynthetic Organisms" (Box 498)
        - "Free Radicals in Functional Biochemical and Biological Systems are Studied by ESR Spectroscopy" (Box 498)
        - "The Integrity of Science" (Box 498)
        - "Is DNA the Secret of Life?" (Box 498)
        - "The Molecular Origins of Biochemical and Biological Specificity" (Box 498)
      - 1966 (Box 498)
        - "By Using Nature as a Lab" (Box 498)
        - "The Elusive Code of Life: Is DNA Really the Master Key to Heredity?" (Box 498)
        - "Feasibility of Biological Recovery from Nuclear Attack" (Box 498)
        - "Is Biology a Molecular Science?" (Box 498)
      - 1967 (Box 498)
        - "The Biosynthesis of Tobacco Mosaic Virus RNA: Relationships to the Biosynthesis of Virus-Specific Ribonuclease-Resistant RNA" (Box 498)
        - "Discussion" (Box 498)
        - "Duty of Science in the Ecological Crisis" (Box 498)
        - "The Eroding Integrity of Science" (Box 498)
        - "Is Science Getting Out of Hand?" (Box 498)
        - "The Killing of a Great Lake" (Box 498)
        - "A Landmark in National Concern" (Box 498)
        - "Letter to the Editor concerning Chemistry and DNA" (Box 498)
        - "Needed: A Continuing Partnership of Scientists and Citizens" (Box 498)
        - "Rod Length in Protein-Stripped Tobacco Mosaic Virus" (Box 498)
        - "Science and Moral Responsibility" (Box 498)
        - "A Scientist Views Pollution" (Box 499)
        - "A Turning Point in the Human Habitation of the Earth" (Box 499)
      - 1968 (Box 499)
        - "The Apollo Program--A Tragic Absurdity" (Box 499)
        - "The Balance of Nature" (Box 499)
        - Center magazine (Box 499)
        - "The Dual Crisis in Science and Society" (Box 499)
        - "Electron Spin Resonance of Iron-Nitric Oxide Complexes with Amino Acids, Peptides and Proteins" (Box 499)
        - "Environmental Health--A New Challenge to University Education and Research" (Box 499)
        - "Environmental Pollution" (Box 499)
        - "Failure of the Watson-Crick Theory as a Chemical Explanation of Inheritance" (Box 499)
        - "Frail Reeds in a Harsh World" (Box 499)
        - "Global Effects of Environmental Pollution" (Box 499)
        - "Lake Erie, Aging or Ill?" (Box 499)
        - "Nature Unbalanced: How Man Interferes with the Nitrogen Cycle" (Box 499)
        - "Nature Under Attack" (Box 499)
        - "Pollution: Time to Face the Consequences" (Box 499)
        - "Protecting the Environment: The Myth of Technological Competence" (Box 499)
        - "Statement on Chemical and Biological Warfare" (Box 499)
        - Statements on Vietnam (Box 499)
        - "Symposium: Life Processes" (Box 499)
      - 1969 (Box 499)
        - Book review of America the Raped (Box 499)
        - "Can We Survive?" (Box 499)
        - "The Crisis in the Environment" (Box 499)
        - "The Ecological Frame of Man" (Box 499)
        - "Electron Spin Resonance Signals in Injured Nerve" (Box 499)
        - "Evaluation of the Biosphere" (Box 499)
        - "Isolation and Identification of a Paramagnetic Complex from the Livers of Carcinogen-Treated Rats" (Box 499)
        - "Man in Today's Environment: Will He Survive?" (Box 499)
        - "Molecular Biology: Medical Fact or Laboratory Dogma?" (Box 499)
        - "Transitory Free Radicals in Irradiated Animal Tissues" (Box 499)
      - 1970 (Box 499)
        - "Beyond the Teach-In" (Box 499)
        - The Effects of 2-Acetylaminofluorene and Nitrite on Free Radicals and Carcinogenesis in Rat Liver" (Box 499)
        - "Present Benefits and Future Risks" (Box 499)
      - 1971 (Box 499)
        - "Environment is Not a Motherhood Issue" (Box 499)
        - Reference notes for unidentified article (Box 499)
      - 1972 (Box 499)
        - "Alliance for Survival" (Box 499)
        - "Alternative Approaches to the Environmental Crisis" (Box 499)
        - "Breaking the Laws of Ecology" (Box 499)
        - Concerning The Closing Circle (Box 499)
        - "Critique of Recommendations from the United Nations Conference on the Human Enviroment" (Box 499)
        - "Do Nuclear Plants Make Deadly Neighbors?" (Box 499)
        - "The Environmental Cost of Economic Growth" (Box 499)
        - "General Education and the Environment" (Box 499)
        - "A Healthy Environment: The Life-or-Death Challenge" (Box 500)
        - "Motherhood in Stockholm" (Box 500)
        - "Must the World Take a Power Cut?" (Box 500)
        - "The Population Problem" (Box 500)
        - "Science and Social Action" (Box 500)
        - "Scientist and Citizen" (Box 500)
      - 1973 (Box 500)
        - "Radiosensitivity and the Ascorbic Acid Electron Spin Resonance Doublet" (Box 500)
        - "A Special Anaysis of American Railroads" (Box 500)
      - 1976, "Energy the Key: It Affects Environment, Prices; We have an Answer in the Sun" (Box 500)
      - 1977 (Box 500)
        - Politiks magazine article (Box 500)
        - "Solar Energy: Myths and Motives" (Box 500)
      - 1978 (Box 500)
        - "Formation of Mutagens in Beef and Beef Extract During Cooking" (Box 500)
        - Hospital Practice articles (Box 500)
        - "How Solar Power Creates Jobs" (Box 500)
        - "Isolation of Mutagens from Bacterial Nutrients Containing Beef Extract" (Box 500)
        - "Mutagenic Analysis of Complex Samples of Aqueous Effluents, Air Particulates, and Foods" (Box 500)
      - 1981, "Talking to a Mule" (Box 500)
      - 1983, "Ethanol" (Box 500)
      - 1984 (Box 500)
        - "Environmental Dangers" (Box 500)
        - "Jackson's Candidacy Will Compel Reagan to Face Basic Issues" (Box 500)
        - "Jackson's Historic Campaign" (Box 500)
      - 1985 (Box 500)
        - "Environmental Impacts of Expanded Utilization of Nuclear Energy" (Box 500)
        - "Quando il pesticida non è uguale per tutti" (Box 500)
      - 1989 (Box 500)
        - "The Hazards of Risk Assessments" (Box 500)
        - "Let's Get Serious About Pollution Prevention" (Box 500)
        - "Lezione di ecologia" (Box 500)
        - "Why We Have Failed" (Box 500)
      - 1992, "If I Were President" (Box 500)
      - 1994, "A Turning Point in the Political History of Dioxin" (Box 500)
      - 2000, Global Økologi (Box 500)
      - 2009, "Molecular Genetics: An Example of Faulty Communication Between Science and the Public" (Box 500)
      - Undated, Drafts concerning science and society (Box 500)
    - Books (Box 500)
      - Air Pollution, draft, from series Environmental Issues edited by Commoner, circa 1971, (3 folders) (Box 500)
      - The Closing Circle, reviews and news clippings, 1971-1974, (5 folders) (Box 501)
      - Making Peace with the Planet (Box 501)
        - Chapter 1-4 drafts, circa 1989, (4 folders) (Box 501)
        - Chapter 5-10 drafts, notes and inserts, circa 1989, (9 folders) (Box 502)
        - Complete drafts, 1989-1990, (6 folders) (Box 503)
        - Publishers' catalog, 1990 (Box 503)
      - The Politics of Energy, reviews, 1979 (Box 503)
      - The Poverty of Power (Box 503)
        - Draft, 1975, (3 folders) (Box 503)
        - Reviews, 1976-1977, (3 folders) (Box 504)
      - Science and Survival, reviews, 1966-1967 (Box 504)
      - Untitled draft in binder, 1964, undated (Box 504)
    - Contracts and correspondence, 1971-1972, undated (Box 504)
    - "The Hamburger Papers: Collection of Writings on Formation of Mutagens in Beef During Cooking," 1977-1978, (2 folders) (Box 504)
    - Speaking engagements (Box 504)
      - Chronological file (Box 504)
        - 1957-1962, 1970-1978, (2 folders) (Box 504)
        - 1979, July 23-Nov. 13, (8 folders) (Box 505)
        - 1979, Nov. 14-1980, Mar. 24, (9 folders) (Box 506)
        - 1980, Mar. 27-June 27, (9 folders) (Box 507)
        - 1980, July 15-1988, June 28, (10 folders) (Box 508)
        - 1988, Aug. 10-1989, Oct. 21, (10 folders) (Box 509)
        - 1989, Oct. 26-Dec. 29, undated, (3 folders) (Box 510)
      - Declined or cancelled, 1980-1981, 1988-1992, (3 folders) (Box 510)
      - Inquiries, 1980 (Box 511)
      - Itineraries and travel arrangements, 1978-1989, (5 folders) (Box 511)
    - Speeches, conference papers, and testimonies (Box 511)
      - 1956-1966, (4 folders) (Box 511)
      - 1967-1969, June, (8 folders) (Box 512)
      - 1969, July-1974, (8 folders) (Box 513)
      - 1976-1994, (6 folders) (Box 514)
  - Subject File, 1942-2008 (Box 514-528)
    The Subject File holds organization files, biographical material, including items from Commoner's military service, a file on Linus Pauling and their work together opposing nuclear weapons testing, documents from Commoner's consultant work concerning the dioxin accident in Seveso, Italy, photographs and portraits of Commoner, and other topical material. The organizations represented in the Subject File that were central to Commoner's career include the American Association for the Advancement of Science (AAAS), Center for the Biology of Natural Systems (CBNS), the Citizens Party, the Greater St. Louis Citizens' Committee for Nuclear Information, and the Scientists' Institute for Public Information (SIPI).
    Material types include correspondence, biographical material, digital content, photographs, reports, and printed matter.
    Arranged alphabetically by topic or name of organization or person. File structure of the digital content maintained as received.
    - Air Warden Service manuals, 1942 (Box 514)
    - American Association for the Advancement of Science (AAAS) (Box 514)
      - Committee on Environmental Alterations (Box 514)
        - "Data on the U.S. Economy of Relevance to Environmental Problems," 1971 (Box 514)
        - "Electric Power Consumption and Human Welfare I," 1972, (2 folders) (Box 514)
        - "Electric Power Consumption and Human Welfare II," 1972, (2 folders) (Box 515)
        - "Electric Power Consumption and Human Welfare III," 1972, (2 folders) (Box 515)
        - "Electric Power Consumption and Human Welfare," appendices, 1972 (Box 515)
      - Committee on Science in the Promotion of Human Welfare (Box 515)
        - "The Integrity of Science," 1962-1966, (3 folders) (Box 515)
        - Miscellany, 1958-1963 (Box 516)
      - Committee on the Social Aspects of Science, 1956, undated (Box 516)
    - Anti-nuclear activism, 1977-1978 (Box 516)
    - Awards and honors (Box 516)
      - "Barry Commoner Lifetime Achievement Award," color photographs of reception, speeches, and award presentation, 2007, mss59774_206_001
      - Certificates, See containers OV 15-OV 16, same heading (Box OV 15-OV 16)
      - Photographs, 1973 (Box 516)
    - Biographical material, 1970-1985, undated (Box 516)
    - Calendars, 1968-1973, 1988, 2000-2006, (5 folders) (Box 516)
    - Center for the Biology of Natural Systems (CBNS) (Box 517)
      - "Biomass energy" binder, 1979-1980, (2 folders) (Box 517)
      - CBNS Notes (periodical), 1968-1973, (2 folders) (Box 517)
      - "Energy" binder, 1975, (2 folders) (Box 517)
      - "Energy Vulnerability of Agriculture" binder, 1975, (1 folder) (Box 517)
      - "Energy Vulnerability of Agriculture" binder, 1975, (3 folders) (Box 518)
      - Environmental health science research grant application, 1965 (Box 518)
      - "Funding" binder, 1974-1976 (Box 518)
      - "Grants" binder, 1968-1973, (3 folders) (Box 518)
      - "Grants" binder, 1968-1973, (1 folder) (Box 519)
      - Miscellany, 1968-1978, 2003 (Box 519)
      - News clippings, 1975-1995, (2 folders) (Box 519)
      - Program of environmental education for students from developing countries, 1976-1977, (2 folders) (Box 519)
      - Research projects, binder 1, 1971-1972, (2 folders) (Box 519)
      - Research projects, binder 2, 1971-1972, (3 folders) (Box 520)
      - Research projects, binder 3, 1972-1973, (3 folders) (Box 520)
      - Research proposal on inorganic nitrogen fertilizer, 1973 (Box 521)
    - Citizens Party (Box 521)
      - "The Citizens Party: A Third Party Story," by Dan Lieberman, circa 1985 (Box 521)
      - Correspondence, 1980-1981 (Box 521)
      - Itineraries, 1979-1980 (Box 521)
      - Membership lists, 1976-1983, undated See also container OV 16, Citizens Party membership list (Box 521)
      - Miscellany, 1980, undated (Box 521)
      - National and regional committees and conventions, 1980-1981 (Box 522)
      - News clippings, binders 1-5, 1979-1980, (7 folders) (Box 522)
      - News clippings, loose, 1979-1991, (2 folders) (Box 522)
      - Publicity, 1980-1981, undated, (2 folders) (Box 523)
      - Speeches and writings, 1980-1983, undated, (2 folders) (Box 523)
    - Columbia University professorship (Box 523)
      - Correspondence, 1970-1971 (Box 523)
      - Miscellany, 1970-1971, undated (Box 523)
    - Egan, Michael, circa 2007 (Box 523)
    - Eightieth birthday, 1997 See also container OV 16, same heading (Box 523)
    - Energy, 1976-1980 (Box 523)
    - "Environmental Pollution" binder, circa 1966 (Box 523)
    - Genetic inheritance manuscript, unknown author, no date (Box 523)
    - Greater St. Louis Citizens' Committee for Nuclear Information (Box 523)
      - Baby tooth survey, 1958-1960, 2003 (Box 523)
      - Conference binder, 1963 (Box 523)
      - Founding documents and miscellany, 1958-1966 (Box 524)
      - Index to publications, 1966 (Box 524)
      - Nuclear Information (periodical), 1958-1964, (6 folders) (Box 524)
    - Hamburgers and cancer, news clippings, 1978 (Box 524)
    - Miscellaneous correspondence, 1961, 1979-1980, 2002-2008 (Box 524)
    - Notebooks for ideas and reminders (Box 524)
      - 1947-1954 (Box 524)
      - 1956-1974, undated, (4 folders) (Box 525)
    - "Nuclear power" binder, 1975-1976, (2 folders) (Box 526)
    - Passport, 1962 (Box 526)
    - Patents, 1954, 1965 (Box 526)
    - Pauling, Linus (Box 526)
      - "An Appeal by American Scientists to the Governments and People of the World" (Box 526)
        - Draft of letter and printed copies, 1957 (Box 526)
        - Signers and contact lists, 1957-circa 1958 (Box 526)
      - Correspondence, 1957-1968, undated (Box 526)
      - Newspaper clippings, 1959-1960 (Box 526)